fifa.com 2018-12-22

# Privacy Policy - FIFA.com

**Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA)**

**FIFA-Strasse 20**  
**8044  Zurich**  
**Switzerland**

For any definition used in this Privacy Policy, please refer to Our Terms located at <http://www.fifa.com/legal/tos.html>. Please read the following to learn more about Our Privacy Policy and the ways in which We use Your information before You proceed with use of the FIFA Digital Platforms.

This Privacy Policy has been drafted in English and has been translated into other languages. In the event of any discrepancy between the English and the translated texts, the English text shall prevail and be used to solve doubts of interpretation.

Date of issue of this Privacy Policy: May 2018

**International Transfer**

YOUR INFORMATION IS PROCESSED IN SWITZERLAND, AND MAY BE PROCESSED ELSEWHERE DEPENDING ON THE LOCATION OF AFFILIATES, BUSINESS PARTNERS, AND OTHER ENTITIES WHO ARE PERMITTED TO ACCESS SUCH INFORMATION UNDER THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY (AND SUCH LOCATIONS OUTSIDE THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA (“EEA”) MAY INCLUDE COUNTRIES WHICH MAY NOT AFFORD THE SAME LEVEL OF PROTECTION OF SUCH DATA AS THE COUNTRY FROM WHICH YOU PROVIDED THE INFORMATION). IF WE DO PROCESS YOUR INFORMATION OUTSIDE THE EEA, WE WILL TAKE ALL REASONABLE STEPS TO ENSURE THAT YOUR INFORMATION IS TREATED AS SAFELY AND SECURELY AS IT WOULD BE WITHIN SWITZERLAND AND UNDER THE SWISS DATA PROTECTION ACT, AS AMENDED FROM TIME TO TIME (“DPA”) AND THE GDPR INCLUDING: PUTTING INTO PLACE DATA PROTECTION AGREEMENTS SUCH AS THE EU MODEL CLAUSES. BY ACCESSING OR USING THE FIFA DIGITAL PLATFORMS OR SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, YOU SPECIFICALLY AGREE TO THAT TRANSFER AND ANY RELATED PURPOSES.

**The collection of information and how We use it**

The collection and use of Your information will always have a lawful basis, either because it is necessary for Our performance of a contract with You, because You have consented to Our use of Your information or because it is in Our legitimate interests. Specifically, We may use Your data for the following purposes: to provide and improve the FIFA Digital Platforms, Services, or FIFA Content, their features, to administer Your membership, and to enable Users to enjoy and easily navigate the FIFA Digital Platforms.

**The information We collect from You**

FIFA collects information when You register for an account and when You enter transactions, promotions or sweepstakes. The information collected may include but is not limited to the following personal information: email address, last name, first name, country of residence, date of birth, gender, screen name, password, ID addresses and opt-in for game and FIFA Content preferences. In order to process some of Your transactions through the FIFA Digital Platforms, We may also ask for Your credit card number and billing information.

**Cookies**

We use “cookies” when you visit the FIFA Digital Platforms. Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](http://www.fifa.com/legal/cookie-policy.html).

**Automatic Information**

FIFA automatically collects some information about Your computer when You visit the FIFA Digital Platforms, regardless of whether You have registered for an account or not by just browsing Our servers. For example, FIFA will collect Your IP address, web browser software, and referring website. We also may collect information about Your location or Your online activity on the FIFA Digital Platforms. Collecting this information helps FIFA customise Your user experience and to monitor and analyse Your use of the FIFA Digital Platforms and the Services. This information is also used for the FIFA Digital Platforms’ technical administration and for the optimisation of the FIFA Digital Platforms’ usability and functionalities.

**How We use Your information**

FIFA uses billing information (such as cardholder name, credit card number, and expiration date) for the purpose of completing the transaction concluded on the FIFA Digital Platforms.

We use other information about You for the following general purposes: to provide You with the Services You request; to manage Your account, including processing bills; to communicate with You in general; to respond to Your questions and comments; to notify You about special offers that may be of interest to You; to prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities; to enforce Our Terms located at <http://www.fifa.com/legal/tos.html>; and as otherwise described to You at the point of collection.

Aggregate information shall also be used to customise the advertising. In using the FIFA Digital Platforms, You expressly entitle FIFA to collect and process Your information, in particular for such marketing and customisation of the Services. You may always revoke Your consent by deleting Your account.

**Phishing**

Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to FIFA. Safeguarding information to help protect You from identity theft is a top priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request Your credit card information, Your account ID, login password or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited email or telephone communication.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

FIFA may send information about You to third parties when:

a) You specifically acknowledge and agree that We may disclose Your information to the following third parties contributing to the delivery of the Services: Coca-Cola and Panini for the Panini Digital Sticker Album, McDonalds for the McDonald’s FIFA World Cup™ Fantasy, Hisense for the Fan Dream Team, Hyundai for the FIFA World Cup™ Match Predictor.

b) We need to share Your information to provide the product or Service You have requested; or

c) We provide the information to companies who work on behalf of FIFA under processor agreements providing for the required safeguards for Your information in accordance with applicable data protection laws; or

d) We respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process; or

e) We believe it is necessary, as determined in Our sole discretion, to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, emergency situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Our Terms located at <http://www.fifa.com/legal/tos.html>, or as otherwise required by law.

**Security**

We want You to feel confident about using the FIFA Digital Platforms. For that reason, We have implemented reasonable technical and organisational measures designed to secure Your information from accidental loss and from unauthorised access, use, alteration or disclosure. However, the internet is an open system and We cannot guarantee that unauthorised third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use Your information for improper purposes.

If You communicate with FIFA by email, You should note that the secrecy of internet email is uncertain. By sending sensitive or confidential email messages or information which are not encrypted, You accept the risk of such uncertainty and possible lack of confidentiality over the internet.

**Your rights**

You have the following rights under the DPA and GDPR, which this Privacy Policy and Our use of Your information have been designed to uphold:

a) the right to be informed about Our collection and use of information;

b) the right of access to the information We hold about You;

c) the right to rectification if any information We hold about You is inaccurate or incomplete;

d) the right to be forgotten – i.e. the right to ask Us to delete any personal data We hold about You (We only hold Your personal data for a limited time, but if You would like Us to delete it sooner, please contact Us;

e) the right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of Your information;

f) the right to data portability (obtaining a copy of Your information to re-use with another service or organisation);

g) the right to object to Us using Your information for particular purposes; and

h) rights with respect to automated decision-making and profiling.

If You have any cause for complaint about Our use of Your information, please contact Us using the contact form at <http://www.fifa.com/contact/form.html>. We may require You to provide verification of Your identity. If We are unable to help, You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (“FDPIC”) or the competent Information Commissioner in the EU (where applicable). Please note that in certain circumstances We may withhold access to Your information where We have the right to do so under current data protection legislation.

**Updating/deleting Your information**

You may review, correct, update, change or delete Your personal information at any time by accessing Your account on the FIFA Digital Platforms. We will accommodate Your request for deletion, if We do not have any legal obligation to retain the record (for logged-in Users: _<http://www.fifa.com/account/index.html> or through the FIFA App)_.

**Links to Other Sites**

If any part of the FIFA Digital Platforms links to other websites, those websites do not operate under this Privacy Policy. If You choose to visit an advertiser or click on another third-party link, You will be directed to that third party’s website. We do not exercise control over third-party websites and therefore recommend You examine the privacy statements posted on these other websites to understand their procedures for collecting, using and disclosing personal information.

**Our policy towards children**

We do not on purpose collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or legal guardian becomes aware that his or her child under 13, or ward under 13, has provided Us with personal information without their consent, he or she should delete the account (refer to: Updating/deleting Your information). If We become aware that a child under 13 has provided Us with personal information without such consent, We will delete such information from Our files.

**Withdrawal of Consent**

**In the event consent was given, You have the right to withdraw such consent given at any time by sending a written notice to Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA), FIFA-Strasse 20, 8044 Zurich, Switzerland or an email to** [dataprotection@fifa.org](mailto:dataprotection@fifa.org) **.**

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. If We amend this Privacy Policy, any changes will be immediately posted on the FIFA Website and You will be deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of the FIFA Digital Platforms following the alterations. We shall place an updated version on this page of the FIFA Website. The FIFA Website and/or the FIFA App may also provide notices of changes to this Privacy Policy or other matters by displaying notices or links to notices to You generally on or within the FIFA Digital Platforms.

**Contact**

**If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at[dataprotection@fifa.org](mailto:dataprotection@fifa.org) or by post to Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA), FIFA-Strasse 20, 8044 Zurich, Switzerland. FIFA’s representative in the EU may be contacted as follows: VGS Datenschutzpartner UG, Am Kaiserkai 69, 20457 Hamburg, Germany.**

**Precedence**

In the event that the provisions of this Privacy Policy conflict with the provisions of a third-party Privacy Policy on the FIFA Digital Platforms, the provisions of this Privacy Policy shall prevail.

**Jurisdiction and applicable law**

This Privacy Policy and all matters arising out of or related to this Privacy Policy shall be governed by the substantive laws of Switzerland, without regard to conflicts of laws and principles thereof.

Any controversy, claim or dispute between You and FIFA arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the competent Courts of the City of Zurich 1, and each party hereby irrevocably consents to the jurisdiction and venue of such Court.
